You know, binaries are not um binary. Um
you know, there there are many things,
right? They might be just
Dude, what a quote. Richard put that in
the beginning of the podcast. That is
going to be our hook for this podcast.
That's amazing. Binaries are not binary.
Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical think, right?
Yeah, dude.
[Music]
One of the things we love the most as
hackers, right, is people or industries
that are just pushing the boundaries of
what are possible. They're on the
bleeding edge and they're asking the
tough questions and pushing industries
forward, right? And that I just want to
be clear is why we've had Threat Locker
on as a sponsor of this podcast for so
long is they are doing that for the
zerorust industry. They're constantly
coming up with innovative solutions to
push the industry forward. And the
latest one that they've come up with is
threat locker user store, right? Because
one of the main problems with zero trust
is everything has to be validated on the
last mile, right? There has to be a
response team that's approving
applications as it's coming through. Um
and that's burdensome to the user. And
so they decided to preload that compute,
right? and and approve a set of
applications in advance that threat
locker users can uh utilize to
accomplish their business goals. For
example, if they're trying to download
sketchy PDF file
reader.exe, instead the user store will
give them instant access to Adobe
Acrobat saying, "Hey, why don't you open
it with this one instead?" Um, rather
than having to go through the whole
response team. It's instantaneous. It's
quick. It's pre-loaded. That's another
way that Threat Locker is pushing the
industry forward. All right, let's go
back to the show.
All right, hackers. I just got off an
episode with space raccoon Eugene Lim,
the bug bounty legend. And this episode
is freaking fire. You guys are going to
love this. Eugene is writing a book uh
that's going to be re released soon
called from day zero to zero day. And it
is about vulnerability research, how to
get into it from the perspective of
somebody who kind of started in bug
bounty, right? So, if any of you guys
are looking to take that extra um deep
dive and kind of go towards that
vulnerability research realm, then this
is an awesome book for you. For the rest
of the podcast, we are going to kind of
go through all of the chapters of the
book. And I asked Eugene, okay, listen,
um each of these chapters has one little
tidbit of gold in it that you got to
give to the listeners. And then he just
kind of gives that to us here on the
pod. So, um you know, you'll get a lot
of value out of this podcast. A lot of
the tips that he gives and the
perspectives um are extremely valuable,
but of course getting your hands on the
book is going to provide a much more
in-depth um understanding of all these
things that he's talking about. So
Eugene was kind enough to give us uh a
discount code for the critical thinking
listeners. The discount code is zeroday
deal. We'll go ahead and put that on the
screen now. Zeroday deal. And that gets
you 30% off when you buy through no
starch. Um I have bought the book. Uh
Richard put the confirmation up on the
screen now. um and I will be reading it
especially after uh this episode and
there's also a free chapter uh on binary
taxonomy which is essentially what are
the different types of binaries how can
you reverse them um you know what when
you look at a binary how do you you know
know the next step helpful chapter
that's available for free now so if you
want even more of a of a taste of the
book you can go grab that um let me see
let me look at my notes real quick um
yes also we are going to buy six copies
of this book and uh give it away to the
critical thinkers tier in Discord. So,
if you're not already in the critical
thinkers tier, head over to
ctvb.show/isord, hop on in there um and
you'll have a chance at winning one of
those six copies that we're going to
give out to the community as a way to
support Eugene and thank him for coming
on the podcast and sharing um such
amazing tidbits. So, um I think that is
it. Yep, that's it. Um, enjoy this
episode with Space Racer [__] Eugene
Lim, the man, the myth, the legend, and
the guy for any of you watching on
YouTube, uh, that this plushy is related
to right here. All right, let's
go. All right, my man Eugene, welcome
back to the pod, man. It has been what,
uh, 117 episodes since you last came on
the pod, so thanks for coming back on,
man. Yeah, it's great to be back. Nice
to be talking to you again, Justin.
Yeah, man. Um, that's crazy. The pod has
evolved quite a bit since that first I
think you were the first I think you
were the first guest interview we did on
the pod. Uh so I don't even know if I
want to tell people about that actually.
Like I'm sure that episode was super
sketchy because in the beginning we were
figuring out so many things. Uh but I
appreciate you bearing with me when I
was a less experienced podcaster. No, I
bet. I mean, I I kind of also don't want
people to read that because I I kind of
recall talking about like using an Excel
sheet to keep track of my targets back
then. Oh my gosh. Yeah, we we were it
was a different it was a different era.
It was a different era back then. Um but
we are moving into a new era and that
era will be supplemented by uh
additional learning materials uh that
are being released and the top of that
list is from day zero to zero day which
is your new book. What a title man
that is that is beautiful. I love that.
Yeah, it's really interesting story
about that actually because when I first
pitched this book uh to no touch uh the
title was uh product security assessment
and you know just straight product
security assessment. Yeah, product
security assessments like so so exciting
so cool. Um but obviously you know I'm
glad it's evolved since then and yeah
dude did did you come up with this
yourself? Did the team come up with it?
Did Dar come up with it? you know. No, I
came I came up with it. I think, you
know, I was just kind of playing around
because they were just like, "Hey, think
of a better title." Um, kind of boring
right now. I was like, "Okay, go back
and think about it." So, yeah, that was
an interesting process. Yeah, that's
great, man. I love how they're just
like, "Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. So, we're
going to need you to go back and come up
with a better title than what you've
got." Yeah. Boring.
That's good, man. Um, okay. So, I I
guess I I'm really excited to get my
hands on this thing. Um, I'd like to
hear a little bit, you know, you
released the the table of contents uh
for what what the contents are going to
be. And it looks to me like this book is
um on vulnerability research, right? and
how to how to get rolling on that, which
I think is an amazing topic because
vulnerability research is such a niche
skill. And so much of it is like, all
right, now I'm going to go do
vulnerability research, you know, and
you're like, I don't know how the heck
to do that, but I'm going to try to go
find Bones, you know. Um, so I think
this could be a great primer on on where
to start. It seems to me like you focus
a lot on uh a little bit more of the
binary uh like exploitation aspect, the
reversing aspect of it. And you know, I
I I've just got the the chapter titles
um since the full book hasn't been
released yet. But um you know, I'm
wondering where my first question when I
look at this is when I think about you,
Eugene, you know, I think about the time
that we've spent together hacking,
right, personally, which has been mostly
focused on like web and mobile related
targets. Um, and I know that you've
pivoted a little bit over the years into
a little bit more of a binary um,
exploitation realm. Um, and I'm
wondering if the stuff that we talked
about, the stuff that we've worked on
together, you know, doing the more web
aspects are covered in this book or
whether this is targeted a little bit
more towards binary exploitation.
Yeah. So, I think, you know, one of the
key things distinguishing like web to
binary kind of exploitation obviously is
the kind of attack vectors like you you
kind of wouldn't have an SSRF. um and
you wouldn't stop there. You would try
to get to um some kind of binary
exploit. Um but what I tried to
highlight here was that there are
actually a lot of common um approaches,
right? There is like code review um
source and sync analysis. Um there is um
you know trying to get a better sense of
what's going on within the target, you
know, through debugging or reverse
engineering. Um, so while we're not
really focusing on web attack vectors
per se, um, I think the vir discovery
aspect of things is is still important
and that's not something I focus on in
terms of binary exploitation. So I'm not
going like, you know, heat funue or, you
know, moving things around in memory,
but I'm focusing on like how do you get
to that first exploit, right? Um, that
first vulnerability and you can go as
far as you want with that, but that's
another book. I'm focusing on that
discovery. um how do you kind of break
down a target even if it's a web binary
or even if it's a web server um there's
still many many ways to exploit
something um whether regardless of what
attack service you're using these days
okay I got you so it's a little bit more
about like the metagaming of
vulnerability research you know like
like what approaches we should take
regardless of what um you know type of
target we're going at after to to sort
of land on hey here's my first my first
bug or my first results from SEC
security research or vulnerability
research. Yeah. And you know there's a
ton of like CVEes and and you know zero
days that are basically web
vulnerabilities, right? Um it's just
that the approach is a little different
because most times the people discover
them you know through reverse
engineering the web binary or source
code review. Um it's a little different
from the typical blackbox approach. Um
that I think kind of sets apart how we
used to approach targets in bug bounty.
I mean obviously some overlap these days
but um and how we see it in in Bombay
research. Yeah, it's a different world
man. You know a lot of people take um a
vulnerability research approach to bug
bounty and and then you know will and
that's great sometimes you know they
find zero days and those get spread you
know across all the bug bounty programs
and you get you get results from it. Um
but it is a very different skill having
sort of like a blackbox um environment
and and trying to trying to test through
it. And I and I think it's also very
different than what a lot of people
um perceive from like a an AP
perspective as well. like if you're if
you're working um I I've just
anecdotally spoken to some of my my
friends that have worked in in that sort
of environment but from what I
understand it's very rehearsed you know
like like a lot of these um operations
that are happening uh they're spending
more time doing the the zero day
analysis right they're saying okay I
know that our target you know over here
is using this software stack or whatever
right um so I'm going to go download
that you know reproduce that whole
environment find a zero day and then
utilize that against my my target,
right? That's the normal flow. Versus
like with Bug Bounty, it's like, "All
right, let's like just show up and just
guess at what's happening and like hack
stuff." So, it's um there's there's a
bunch of different realms to all this
and and Bug Bounty definitely doesn't
correlate onetoone with with um any of
them, I think. Yeah. And I think it's
super interesting as well having, you
know, seeing more crossovers because I I
think you had a episode with Chiron
couple. Yeah. So met him super cool guy,
right? And you see the things they come
in bug bounty have a completely
different approach and it's pretty
amazing the kind of things they find and
the other way around as well. Yeah.
Yeah. And then and then even within bug
bounty right there's more like the pone
to own realm and stuff like that which
is uh a whole different beast. So, um,
yeah, definitely lots of different
strategies that can work, right? You
know, you can do the traditional bug
bounty approach like we did in the
beginning where it's like, all right, we
we show up, we open up our our Kaido or
Burpuite instance and we hack some stuff
or you go the vulnerability route uh
research route um more like Chiron or or
um you know, anybody who's doing
vulnerability research. So, definitely
definitely lots of way to ways to
approach the game. Um, and so I guess
going back to the book though, I love
how it starts with chapter zero. Thank
you for that. That that's great. I love
zero index channel. Yes. Yes. That's uh
that's beautiful. Um do yeah I don't
know when I see stuff like that I'm like
yes this is the this is the right
material that I want to be reading. Um
and then it go so it goes day zero
change analysis and then chapter two is
called mapping code to attack surface.
And when I when I when I read that title
and and actually I want to go through
each one of these chapters and sort of
talk to you a little bit about what of
your what your mentality was with it
because um you know to be all right
Eugene you know I have a little man
crush on you like I've got your little a
little uh you know plushy sitting right
in the background here in my Yeah.
Exactly. Exactly. Um so I really I I
have high expectations for this book.
Um, and I want to go through each one of
these chapters and kind of pick your
brain a little bit about what you're
thinking on each of them. But the one
that one that stood out to me was
chapter 2 mapping code to attack surface
because it really um reflects one of the
principles that I talked about um you
know I talk about whenever I have access
to source code which is um this this one
quote from um Sam Herb who I think you
you might have met at live hacking
events but whenever I was a little bit
younger of a hacker and Sam and I were
hacking together um and I was kind of
looking up to Sam you know as like this
this guy that has been more experienced
in industry um he says I always like to
play this game called the find the
endpoint game. And essentially, you
know, he's using an app and he looks at,
you know, his his HTTP proxy and says,
"Oh, here's an API endpoint. Let me go
find where that API endpoint is
is, you know, triggered in the client
side code and where it is, you know,
defined in the server side code." and
then just kind of work backwards from
there like what routes are adjacent to
that, what functionality is adjacent to
that and then just use that to make sure
you're getting the full picture of the
application and I just that's such a
simple concept and it has worked so well
for me whenever I've done source code
review. Um so that's kind of what I
imagined this chapter 2 was about. Is
that like is there is that accurate? Is
there more to that than than um what
I've described here? Yeah. So I think
pretty much that is one of the key
concepts right you know from sync to um
source you know trying to find the
vector to reach the vulnerable um
function that you're looking at um but I
think also part of it was about
expanding uh your definition of what the
attack service is because um this is
something that I wish I learned you know
like three years ago right because you
know you first start obviously with APIs
and endpoints um and at some point you
kind of realize there's there's more to
it right now there's like web RTC there
are other like protocols
that still go over the web for one
reason or another. And the people who
actually take time to understand these,
you know, post message and all kinds of
other client side, they expand their
opportunities so much more. And so I
think that was kind of thing I was
trying to get across as well. It's like,
hey, let's go beyond this one thing and
now you have many things and this kind
of expands all your options as well and
that makes things exciting because then
you can chain them and and bring out a
lot more interesting exploits.
Absolutely, man. It's funny you
mentioned WebRTC cuz I was looking at a
at a target that was using that the
other day and and I don't know maybe you
know you just threw it out there as one
of the adjacent technologies but I have
not seen anything that allows us to like
effectively inspect that traffic. Yeah.
Have you have you looked into that at
all like from a technical perspective or
is that something that you know am I
knocking on the door of some research
that's un unreleased yet or what? Yeah.
I mean, so I I haven't actually looked
at WebRTC specifically, but what has
interested me a lot is the browser APIs
that are available these days, right?
That that there's so much weird stuff
going on that are not just simple HTTP
requests anymore that a browser can do.
Um, and the tooling for that is is is
super interesting because it's is
probably in a binary. You have to do
some kind of um um you could intercept
it, but you you probably do have to do
some kind of debugging as well to get
there. Um, and the crazy thing is that
these days people are writing
applications that use webc to send API
requests. Um, yeah, and there's some
really interesting stuff in there. Yeah,
dude. It's it's uh it's very fascinating
and and I have only because I've been so
siloed in web, you know, a lot of my a
lot of my um research experience, you
know, whether it be and applying that to
IoT and mobile, right? because it does
apply.
Um you know I I feel like my perspective
is a little limited but when when I have
uh you know strayed away from uh HTTP
protocol and focus more on like SIP and
um and like custom binary protocols I'm
thinking of like three or four bugs that
I found in those arena very limited set
of experience but I look back on those
so fondly I'm like yes that was the real
hacker [__] No, I still remember the S
bug that you found in that. I think it
was the biggest biggest Vegas biggest
event, right? Yeah, that was amazing.
That's right, man. I was just I I I
don't know, man. It does really energize
me in a way that um you know, a lot of
other stuff doesn't. And and I guess
just speaking anecdotally personally as
well, like I've talked to a friend
recently who's kind of struggling with
okay, now I'm like three years into Bug
Down Bounty and I'm like um kind of
getting comfortable with everything and
I want
that again. I want that like something
needs to be interesting and new. And um
while I totally understand what he's
saying, like I also am a little bit of a
sucker for just like good old HTTP
vulnerabilities, man. Like like I don't
there's just something inherently about
Justin that just loves to find a
freaking access, you know?
Yeah. Yeah. I don't know. It's just I
think I'm paired pretty well to it
because it's like there's still a lot of
like passion and excitement that comes
out of finding a vulnerability that I've
found like a thousand times before. Um
so I don't know that maybe that's just
me, but definitely, you know, looking
deeper into those different protocols
and stuff like that is really exciting
and I think is a very ripe attack
surface for anybody who's willing to
take that extra dive. Um and and you're
helping people do that with this book.
So yeah. Um, all right. Let's let's
let's backdate it a little bit. We
talked a little bit about mapping code
to attack surface. Talk to me about day
zero and taint analysis. Specifically,
taint analysis is interesting to me
because that is a a very interesting
term that I've seen applied to a lot of
different things and uh I think that
fits the global uh viewpoint of your
book really well. Yeah. So what I found
interesting because um obviously it's
something that we all have picked up
intuitively in this space like you
mentioned code review you know trying to
figure out where the endpoint find the
hidden endpoint right um and that's
essentially it like you're trying to
find the sync which is a vulnerable
function or some kind of exploitable um
part of the code and you're trying to
trace it back to the source which is
where your initial inputs come in and
and you know hopefully there's nothing
along the way um and what I found in in
the binary space was pretty interesting
is that you know it's a fairly technical
term is a term that a lot of PhDs use um
but it's actually something that we
figured out intuitively um at some point
um and the key thing about this is that
once you're doing like code review um
while doing it manually is one way of
doing it um t analysis is this huge
field that you know there's been so much
um research poured into that um in the
katak space um modeling um code basis um
so you can do it completely
automatically that's how like code works
and I guess deep graph works um these
days. Um but there's so much more to it
as well because then how do you quickly
abstract for example a sanitizer or some
kind of function that will break your
flow, right? Um and you're like, okay,
time to look at something else or
something that propagate your um inputs.
Um something that you know might not
obviously look like it's going to pass
your input to somewhere else in the
code, but it does. Um and you just need
to be aware of that. Um, and so a lot of
it is just really kind of exploring,
unpacking this kind of academic sounding
subject but making it practical.
Dude, that's freaking exciting, man. I I
need that. That is what I need. Okay,
that that you know because because there
is a lot of that, right? And and there
is a lot of um I think a lot of really
positive stuff comes out of the academic
research that is done into cyber
security and I think we'd be a fool to
disregard that. But I feel like there's
two juxtaposed worlds. Yeah. Right. In a
in security research in a lot of ways.
You've got the guys that are a little
scrappy like us, you know, that like
that that prefer our our little like
two-page blog post and like, you know,
maybe the research is really in-depth,
but you know, it's pretty to the point.
It's not really necessarily sharing the
journey. You know, it's not really
conducted in a way that is um as
academic sometimes or as thorough. And
then you've got these really, you know,
well-written long academic papers with,
you know, that may may or may not have,
uh, you know, amazing takeaways buried
in them. Uh, but, you know, when we try
to access that that academic research,
sometimes it's a little bit, uh, what's
the word? A little a little bit
overwhelming, you know, because it's
like, I don't know how to read this.
This is like its own language. Um, so
I'm I'm really looking forward to that.
And I think one of the things you said
there that really hit the nail on the
head is um input propagation. That
really resounded with me and it made me
think of
um you know I I want to say man was it
earlier? No it must have been last year
um at the beginning of last year we we
did a little
um stint on the pod into uh WordPress uh
security research. Okay. And you know I
have I was a PHP dev. That was my first
job. Uh and uh like I I felt pretty
confident. I was like, "Yeah, I can read
PHP. Like this isn't a big deal, right?"
But WordPress is its own thing, right?
Like the there's a lot of ways that
there's hooks throughout the WordPress
ecosystem that take your input and
propagate it to other spaces, right? And
if you don't know where those hooks are,
then it's it's very unintuitive the the
code the flow of the code, right? And
you miss a lot of attack surface if
you're not aware of those. Yeah. Um and
and um my my takeaway from that
experience was wow whenever I'm I'm
doing source code review I really need
to understand thoroughly how input
propagates through the system. Um, so
that that makes a lot that that really
aligns with that and and uh yeah, I
think it it is a difficult thing to
figure out how to do and I'm amazed that
yeah, there may be some way to do this,
you know, in a more automated fashion
that that CodeQL or or um other like um
systems would would be able to to trace.
It's pretty sick. Yeah, for sure. I
guess part of it is also like you know
going beyond source code and I guess
we'll talk about this in the later
chapters and you know how you just not
just do this in source code but but in
binaries kind of a gray box approach as
well. Yeah. Yeah. Let's let's definitely
let's definitely do that. So um moving
moving down through the the chapter flow
the next one is automate uh automated
variant analysis. So So here's okay let
me let me just put my cards on the table
here Eugene. Okay my here here are my
cards. Here they are. Um uh what I want
is to go through each one of these
chapters and I want you to give me a
little tidbit of like what I can expect
to take away from this book, right? Cuz
because and this is this is like I said
card shown mutually advantageous to
everybody, right? Uh we get some some
some nice tidbits for free in a two-hour
podcast. Um and you know, we get to get
more interested in the book. So let's
kind of go through here and and and kind
of take tidbits from each each chapter.
So tell me about automated variant
analysis. What do we what's the what's
the 8020 of that of that chapter that we
need to know about? Yeah. So I think one
of the things is that like when you look
at CVs, you know, um they don't often
come in like solo like they come in
batches because uh obviously like
someone discovers a common vulnerable
pattern in in the code and then they
just you know just replicate that across
the code. Um so that's one way to do
automated variant analysis. You might
see a new CVE come in. um it might make
sense to just not just you know dismiss
it and say like hey it's not bother
anymore. It takes time to like break it
down, understand it and then look for
other patterns in the code and you can
find your own zero day from that zero
day, right? Um and then the the second
part of that is then how do you just go
beyond a single target and you go to all
the targets, right? because um uh
sometimes these patterns are replicated
in in many code bases either because
they use the same library or um they
they just we use an open source um um
piece of code, right? And just allows
you to then find everything basically,
right? Um I think you've done something
similar before. I feel like you've done
something like that before, right? Yeah,
very much so. Yes. Yeah. So I guess it's
kind of like putting to words like
things that we kind of know intuitively
and we practice and then you know
crystallizing it um moving forward.
Yeah. Essential man. Uh I I just wanted
to say with that RIP CVE did you see the
whole Did you see the whole thing that
came out? Did you That's crazy, right?
Is the CVE program just being defunded?
Like there was like a one day notice
basically, right? And they just sent
this letter out and everyone was like
what? Like uh that's not good. Yeah. So,
I hope I guess you know it's currently
April 17th when we're recording this.
Um, and uh it's it's my buddy's
birthday. He's a security researcher as
well and he like put he put in a chat
and he's like this is this is my
birthday wish has come true. CVE are
being removed. I'm like what the freak?
Yeah. No CVS, no vulnerabilities, right?
Yeah, man. But that would be such a
pain, you know, if we didn't if we
didn't have access to that data source
because like you mentioned here, it's so
helpful for understanding, okay, what
kind of mistakes have has this target
software made in the past that they
might be, you know, more vulnerable to
in the future. Um, so yeah, I hope I
hope they get that. Yeah. I mean, I saw
this funny tweet where I was like, now
is the time to bring back like bug
track, like that mail mailing list where
people just used to dump zero days and
be like, "All right, bye." Yeah,
bye-bye. Full
disclosure. No coordinating, nothing.
Let's go. Nope. Um, that's crazy, man.
Yeah. I mean, hey, I would I if if
everything got full disclosed, I
wouldn't complain. I I probably would
complain, but I I would be a little bit
happy, too. Uh, so I don't know, man. I
I feel like I feel like over the past
couple years, but Book Bounty is an
amazing thing, man. But but it also does
turn you into a little bit of a green
hat, right? like like I I um I was at
this this Google live hacking event uh a
couple weeks ago and and I I was talking
to a guy that was very instrumental in
making a decision that makes browser
exploitation very difficult uh you know
like from an XSS you know utilizing XSS
perspective and I was like what the
heck's wrong with you like like why
would you do this and he's like dude
we're trying to make things more secure
and I'm
I get
that like, but you know, you just made
my job so much harder. And he's like,
yeah, that's literally my job. And I'm
like, fair enough. Um, so yeah, that
makes sense. Okay, moving to chapter
four. This is binary taxonomy. This is
one of the ones that is available um
online for free now. And uh I I I told
you right before we started recording
that I printed this whole thing out and
I I intended to sit down and read it
last night before the pod in
preparation, but um some family stuff
got in the way, but I did jump over and
it seems to be, you know, just
understanding how different uh you know
environments uh binaries are structured
and and getting access to source code
from different um types of binaries.
Um like can you can you tell me a little
bit more about that? Like is that is
that explanation correct? Yeah, for
sure. I think part of it is also um
trying to write for me like three years
ago, right, when I was doing like web
and you know your friend as well, you
know, because kind of like hey, I've
kind of like learned all these things in
in web and I want to get find something
new, right? And but how do I get there?
And part of it is really just like
demystifying like binary um boundary
research because for a lot of us it's
like whoa I did like sounds hard man um
can't read assembly, you know. Um yes,
that's me. Yes. Right. I'm here. I am
your target audience. Wow. Great. Yeah.
So, so part of it is like, you know,
binaries are not um binary. Um you know,
there there are many things, right? They
might be just
dude, what a quote. Richard put that in
the beginning of the podcast. That is
going to be our hook for this podcast.
That's amazing. Binaries are not binary.
Okay. I'm sorry. Continue. Yeah. And I
mean some of them are literally like
NodeJS apps like bundled into Electron
you knowJS right and you can just unpack
it and read source code. Um some of them
are like Java um where it's pretty much
like an Android app. You can again
decompile them to pretty readable source
code. Yeah. Um you can also what a game
changer right. Exactly. Yeah. Jeez. And
of course some of them are like compiled
code like Golang and but but there's
still a lot more that you can do with
all of that and and so part of this like
introductory chapter to like binary uh
to reverse engineering which is the
second part um is about firstly
demystifying that to make it seem a lot
more approachable is like hey there
multiple ways you can approach this
target um and and you and I you know
we've experienced this before because we
have dealt with like hardware events and
we dealt with you know um software
events right where it wasn't just a web
app anymore. was just this scary looking
like um I I'm not even sure if this like
life hacking was like classified or not,
right? Desktop, let's just go with that.
Um and and what I found in those life
hacking events was that like a lot of
people actually got stuck because they
tried to go back to like web a lot of
the time. But for those who like went a
little bit further and tried to actually
look at this desktop app, they got like
so many bugs, so many interesting bugs.
Um yeah, and and ones that were not that
far below the surface, right? Like I I
think that it was very kind of you uh
Eugene to of all these chapters disclose
this chapter for free online because I
think that this is one of the biggest
game changers and one of the things that
people really do shy away from like
you're saying is like okay it's a binary
that's not me I don't touch that you
know like like but if it's you know if
it's a net binary and you just like drop
it into peak and boom there's the source
code it becomes much much much easier to
find these vulnerabilities. Um, so just
having an understanding of you what kind
of binaries exist out there and what
format you can get them to, you know,
you don't have to throw them all in in
Gedra or whatever and and like jump
through, you know, each individual bit.
Um, you know, that that is an absolute
game changer. So definitely definitely
recommend to the to the viewers, well,
first of course I'll recommend to the
viewers, you need to go buy this right
now uh this book, pre-order this book.
And we actually have a deal uh for you.
When do you want to do that? I guess m
maybe tell you what Eugene, I'll put
something at the beginning of this
podcast actually with this with this
code. But the code is zero day deal and
we get 30% off. Is that is that right?
Yeah. 30%. Yeah. Okay, cool. I'm going
to put that at the beginning so so you
know every everybody who doesn't take as
long to be convinced
exactly can go ahead and grab it. But
you know, absolutely the binary taxonomy
chapter is out there. Um, so I'd
recommend to any of the the viewership
to go read that and at least understand
when you are approaching a binary target
what your options are. Um, because it's
so much easier to work with Java or
decompiled.net than it is to deal with
just blackbox or trying to throw all
this stuff into.
Um, yeah.
Okay, moving back to chapter five. This
one's titled source and sync discovery.
This has been a reoccurring debate on
this
podcast of of where what do we do?
Sources to syncs or syncs to source. Um,
and you've you you've said a couple
times already that it for you it seems
to be a little bit more sync to source.
You know, you identify the vulnerable
portion of the code and then you work
back. Is that always your methodology or
is there any deviation from that?
Um, so I kind of think about it like
this way, right? Because it really
depends on, you know, firstly like
source code analysis. If you have like a
source code, then I think stick to
source makes a lot of sense. Um,
because, you know, it's kind of like you
have a kind of a maze, you know, like
those little mazes you used to use your
pencil and try to like trace it. Um, and
what's the what's the best way you like?
Do you start from all the outside, you
know, entryways or do you start from the
middle and then try to like find a way
out, right? Um, that's kind of the
analogy I use in a book for source code
review. Um, but as you can tell in
reverse engineer, I'm kind of like, you
know, a little bit of both, right? Um,
and I think the key thing is, um,
understanding
um,
understanding all the sources and the
syncs available to you. Um, and part of
it what I discussed later on in the book
is that you know like before like J&GI
lo forJ was a thing, right? um no one
kind of thought about J&GI uh exploits
because it was just this thing that came
up in a conference once you know um and
it kind of faded away. Um and only when
someone like actually like took the time
to understand this conference paper and
and then find an exploit in law forj
everyone was looking for like J&GI um
exploits um moving forward um and and so
depending on how what your understanding
of what sources and syncs are available
to you then there's a lot more options
for you to trace back and forth um and
that's what I try to bring out with um
this chapter in reverse engineering is
that um you have to understand your
target um is it exposing a remote attack
surface is it something like more local
and then that can give you a more
informed decision of which way do you
want to go. Yeah, that absolutely makes
sense. And I love that you said what you
said there about understanding both the
sources and the syncs, right? Because I
think that's where it becomes a little
more nuanced, right? Like we debated on
the podcast a couple times like I think
when Joel was on we used to debate this
often but one of my approaches with all
of this is like when I'm attacking a new
target especially when I'm not time
bound by a live hacking event. Um I want
to spend some time getting intimate with
the app. Right. That's one of our little
things we we we say here on the pod. I I
think that came from me like fumbling my
words sometimes or something like that.
But insight but but it but but it works
right you know you need you need to get
intimate with these apps and you need to
understand you know the nuances of how
they work and for me one of the best
ways to do that is to look at the
sources right where does my data flow
into the application and and how does it
flow through all of the different pieces
you know have I observed in the front
end you know something happening that I
can't trace at the code okay well my
input's getting propagated somewhere
that I don't understand and I need to
figure that out you know and I need to
figure that out early on so that uh you
know when I'm assessing the other parts
of the the codebase I can I can actually
accurately trace what's happening you
know um and and so that's why I always
say like I actually spend a lot of time
looking at sources in the beginning and
and I think that it also um informs what
kind of exploit you want as well right
like not to say that o bypasses don't
exist they absolutely do you know but if
you're looking for a a unothed you know
rce you probably shouldn't go look at
all these o routes first you know like
probably what you should do is focus on
the unoff portions of the codebase right
and how do you get access to those flows
and obviously unoff portions probably
for most apps are going to be a much
smaller subsection so let's narrow it
down let's focus on those and then let's
you know trace those from source to sync
and try to figure out you know what kind
of syncs we can hit um but then
obviously when you're dealing with
larger code bases
that gets super overwhelming, right?
Like like what are there's so many
routes. There's so many places that this
could go. You're kind of forced to do it
backwards where you say, "Okay, well,
um, let me find some code that looks
sketchy." You know, over here we're
constructing an SQL statement in a
little bit of a sketchy way. You know,
is this is this variable actually typed?
You know, like that that sort of thing,
right? Um, uh, and then, you know,
tracing it back up the stack. So I I
think it is a, you know, something that
requires judgment on a on a on a case-to
case basis, right? And and I think, you
know, this chapter will probably add a
little clarity for most people that
don't know how to play that game. Yeah,
for sure. Especially in the context of
like reverse engineering um where you
don't have sometimes you don't have the
source code, but you know, it's this big
blob and you it's kind of scary, but
then you know there's actually a lot of
tools that you can use dynamic analysis
with debuggers to then just trace the
whole flow out for you. Um and that's
what I'm also trying to bring out again
just kind of bridging um this this gap.
Yeah, I I think that is a new world for
me as well in in in the world of binary
analysis tracing all that through. And
I've often thought in the world of
source code review that I should just
sit down and write some tooling relating
to this sometimes because I I often, you
know, it's pretty clear how how all this
works. you know, you you look at a at a
at a function, you know, that that is
tied to a route, right? Yeah. And you
trace the input through it and then you
jump to a different function and there's
this path that that comes, right? And
then sometimes you need to backst step a
little bit in the path and go to a
different execution path, right? And and
I I've thought that and there's like
this VS Code extension that I kind of
use called bookmarks that that will
allow you to like bookmark specific
locations in the code and jump back to
that really quickly. And obviously, you
know, VS Code has like you can jump back
to where your cursor was last and you
can kind of step through the code that
way. But I've al I've always thought
that there needs to be some better
tooling defining vul pathways through
the code. And Eugene, I just thought
about this. How sick would it be if like
you had that and then it would
automatically build out those graphs
that you that we do in every report
where it's like okay here's the source
and then here's the middleware and then
here's the the next code and then here's
the next one and then you know you just
kind of mark the key lines. Yeah. And
then say export pathway and it says okay
code flows from here to here to here to
here to here and you get that snippet
and you just paste it into the report.
Right. That would be that'd be so
helpful man. Oh my god. Yeah. I mean
that's that's the crazy thing right
because like um it's actually like such
a hard problem and when you think about
like
CoQ um and later on reverse engineer I
talk about this tool called anger um
they were all literally written by like
PhDs because right and and part of it is
interesting because obviously they have
the expertise and and the deep
understanding to to really kind of like
I guess it's like computer science like
call graphs and stuff like that. Um
absolutely and and but then also like it
goes into the hands of like researchers
who like have a very different take on
this. It's like we want to find the
vulnerabilities right um and and kind of
bridging those too um between this
really complex tools and you know I want
to find bug kind of vibe uh is is
actually part of the challenge I think.
Yeah, it's a classic software problem
actually, you know, like like we have
the more technical author of the code,
right? And they write it how you know
they try to put themselves in the user's
shoes. Yeah. And uh and try to build a
software that works for them. Uh and but
then you know you've got the normal
user, right? you know and and maybe I
shouldn't represent it this way but like
uh you know it's a classic software
engineering you know thing where it's
like all right think of the user as a
potato you know like they are going to
make every possible mistake that they
could possibly make and your job is to
make the the UI as intuitive and as
simple as possible right um and and yeah
I mean that applies to us you know super
technical researchers as well that you
know sometimes the software isn't always
going to
super intuitive and um and I think
that's why there's a lot of room for
things like this, right? Where you
Eugene have taken the deep dive on some
of these softwares and to and and taken
the the deep dive on some of these, you
know, patterns and uh and make it a
little bit easier um for people to sort
of step into that and feel like, okay,
yeah, I actually do have a little bit of
grip on how some of this stuff works. Um
so that that's great. I appreciate that.
And I need to do that for some of the
softwares that I've I've I've written
and uh and stuff like that as well. Um
okay, chapter six, hybrid binary
analysis.
Hit me. Yeah. So I think what I'm trying
to say here is that um you know you can
you can use static approaches right
where you kind of reverse engineer
something you put in IDA or
greak or whatever and you decompile it
and there's just all this like stuff
that you have to go through. But like
you said, there's some code bases that's
so massive that it's almost impossible
to like do it um statically. Then the
other approach you have is hybrid
analysis where use like Freda, right, to
write hooks um to step through a program
like I guess do peak is something you
can use as well in the debugger. Um and
this this gives you a pretty good um
understanding of the application. Um but
it's only like what you can reach in
that
application. Um and what I'm trying to
do is that you can actually kind of
bridge these two approaches. Um and I
mentioned this earlier there's some
tools like Anger that do something
called like symbolic analysis um where
they try to combine both approaches
static analysis and or simulated like
dynamic analysis to really kind of give
you the best of both worlds right um
what's the challenge with static
analysis is that there's too many things
to look at um and what's the thing about
dynamic analysis is that hey you can
only like look at the things that you
are like stepping through at that time
which is kind of the limited
functionality you can access um through
the app um And by combining the two, you
can actually get a lot more information
but also a lot more focus um in
understanding an application. So this is
kind of the most I think the most like I
think challenging chapter but I think if
you actually understand the tools that
are explained in this chapter and you
walk away with it, you can actually get
really really good um binary um zombie
discovery um as well. Yeah. Yeah, man. I
I I hear you talk about this and and I'
I've I've heard lots of other people
come on the pod and talk about like the
importance of using debuggers and sort
of dynamic analysis and I'm sitting
here, you know, getting ready to ask you
the question like how important is is
dynamic analysis really, you know, um
because it is a pain in the ass to get a
debugger set up sometimes. Like it
really is and I'm sitting here and I'm
realizing whenever I do, you know, I I'm
a big client side hacker, right? Yeah.
Whenever I do client side hacking, where
do I live? I live in DevTools, man. I am
constantly in dev tools, right? and like
is setting break points and and you know
like re reassigning variables so I can
you know simulate pathways through other
parts of the code and quickly validate
whether if I can bypass this one sketchy
looking thing is there even a
vulnerability there in the first place
right um and that's exactly what this is
you know on server side as well um so
yeah it's it's extremely important it if
I if I if I if I needed to spend a
couple days getting dev tools hooked
into a website, I would totally do it,
you know, 100%. Um, and so I think it it
is worth the worth the
pain. And Freda, I mean, Freda opens up
a whole new world too, you know. I I I
think I I talked about this with you
before, you know, at that same event
where where Yeah, actually in in that
that whole flow of that that SIP related
bug, it you know, I was showing you all
this like free to hooks that I had um
into the application, right? that it was
a mobile app at this point and I had to
essentially use the mobile app as a as a
proxy, you know, to send these requests
because I didn't have a good way to send
SIP requests, right? Um, and yeah, I
mean, it's just absolutely essential
when you're dealing with some of these
uh protocols that aren't as built out as
HTTP surrounding like tooling for that.
Um and then and then I remember yeah
Eugene the the moment where you it's all
coming back to me now where on that bug
I was stuck and then Eugene was like
dude you should just patch the binary
and I'm like I'm like the [__] like what
do you mean patch the binary Eugene but
this is this is a perfect thing you know
like like you know this is why I'm glad
you wrote this book because a lot of the
guys in in in the web world right at
that live hacking event wouldn't have
said dude just patch the binary and you
did and that was the right choice right
and and Really all I needed to do in
this specific scenario was like flip one
bit to get a header out of the way, you
know, and and then I can inject my own.
Um, so yeah, dude. And that that that
was very impactful to me as a hacker.
Yeah, I think part of it is really like
expanding expanding your toolbox, right?
Because you know like Freda like I think
most people understand it as like a
mobile like debugger. Um, but you can
actually use Freda on the operating
system, right? like Mac OS and and
Windows and it actually becomes a lot
more powerful for for research as as as
a whole. So that's one thing I actually
demonstrate in there was we use Freda to
um actually find a vulnerability in a
Windows desktop application and I think
that makes it so much more interesting.
Tell tell me about that a little bit
because when I've used on a mobile app,
you know, typically I'm using it on an
Android mobile app and I I have access
to, you know, I decompile the Java code,
I see, okay, this is the function I want
to hook. I grab it, you know, it's got a
nice readable name, that sort of thing,
right? And whenever I need to use Freda
to hook into a native library, it's
like, this is pain, you know, like, and
I got to like figure out all this. So, I
mean, are is it I don't know. That's
kind of how I'm imagining it with
desktop apps. I imagine there's more
nuance to it. Yeah, I guess, you know,
obviously there's like some apps that
are like compiled and stripped with all
the symbols, right? and then you get
like weird function names. It's
basically impossible to figure out
unless you spend a lot of time like
reverse engineering it. Um and then
these there's also other API calls that
we can make. They're like OS level like
Windows API calls that have used very
common names like you know like how we
have browser APIs. Um you have them for
Windows and Mac OS as well. And these
are also common um names that you they
have to call regardless. Um and then
this makes it easier for you to then
kind of understand like at the base
layer what is this application doing.
You may not need to like go all the way
deep into the um internals of the
application but you can understand how
that application is interacting with the
operating system or with the web right
because these are pretty common um um
function names that you can just hook on
and understand.
Dude, that's pivotal. That that makes
that makes so much sense. you know where
where you want to get, you know, where
you want to snag these pieces of
interaction where it's hitting pivotal
pieces of of the operating system or the
browser, whatever. So, you hook on
those. That's that's good. That's great.
Yeah. There you go, dude. Yeah, dude.
It's It's starting, man.
Dude, shut up,
Eugene. I'm gonna do that right now. Um,
no. Uh, that's great. That that
definitely helps. And and the Thank you,
Eugene. This is exactly what I'm looking
for. the the the the quick and dirty
tips. Okay. Um, speaking of quick and
dirty, next chapter, quick and dirty
fuzzing. Talk to me about that because
Okay. Well, first I say talking about
that. Let let me let me yap about it
first and then and then I'll I'll let
you talk about it because I feel like
fuzzing is something that I've talked
about on the pod a couple times before
and I see a lot of high power hackers
use it. Specifically, Fron is like a
notorious fuzzer. He'll just like throw
every character at everything and I'm
like, why are you doing that? you know,
like that seems like such a a a time
sync, right? But then he's like, "Yeah,
you know, I knew from this one dollar
sign being injected into this one spot
that there's like this crazy bug down
the pathway." And I'm like, "Wow, okay."
Um, and and I think it's a hole. I think
it's a hole in my own methodology
personally. Um, so I'm definitely
interested to hear how important this is
to you and your methodology uh attacking
not only web targets, but you know, and
obviously it's more important in in um
in binary related targets.
Yeah. So I think again like pretty much
with the first chapter of the the the
parts the the other parts right this my
first chapter to the fuzzing part. Um,
and the goal of this chapter is really
to just say it's less to demystify it
and also to explain why it's easy to
kind of get started. And that's why I
say quick and dirt, right? Um, because a
lot of times, you know, these days
fuzzing is pretty advanced like people
have like attached like um um debuggers
to it, you know, it's like um basically
guided fuzzing, smart fuzzing as they
say. Um yeah, but the old ways still
work pretty well, which is dumb fuzzing.
Uh and what that means is that you know
you have a vague understanding of the
structure that the application expects
or the web application and you just kind
of go wild with it. You just throw
everything at it, right? Um and my
argument in this chapter is actually
like there's actually a lot of CVs that
you see out there like you you could
have found them with a dumb fuzzer,
right? And so what's the gap, right? The
gap is like, oh, fuzzing is this thing
that seems a bit scary. I don't know
where to start. Um, and so what I do in
this chapter is really introduce a
couple of like, you know, fairly simpler
fuzzes that you can use to then just get
started right away. Um, and you will see
in a lot of the kind of pontto own
writeups. Um, they actually use dumb
fuzzers um to start with, right, to kind
of get your intuition of the app like
like what France was saying, right? It's
like, oh, I I found out that this dollar
sign was weird. Um, and then from there
they can kind of do deeper research. Um,
but the point is just get started. Just
fuzz it, right? Um, and what I hope to
do is that this lowers the barrier of
entry um to the reader and be like,
"Hey, it's actually not that hard. I can
fuzz this target." And you can actually
find a lot of with just just this um
starting point.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm I'm thinking through
that as you're saying it and I'm
thinking, yeah, there's so many there's
so many applications for that and so
many ways that that makes sense even in
a time bounded engagement, right? like
pone or like the live hacking events
where where it's like okay I don't have
time necessarily to build out this smart
you know coverage guided or or you know
um debugger um utilizing fuzzing
environment right I just got to throw
everything at it and then like just give
dedicate a computer to it 24/7 for the
rest of this event you know and just
grab the weird stuff that pops out and
see what I can do with it you know um
and I think there's actually you know in
the web world there's an interesting
application for this as well which is
kind of where I live a little bit, which
is that I've been kind of mulling over,
which is I I think there does need to
be and and there is a a uh possibility
nowadays for a fuzzer that is a little
bit more intelligent that doesn't
require a lot of um configuration in the
web world. And that is by by using LLMs
to process the the body of you know
either the um request body or the
response body and say okay you know
where are these ids that I need you know
and and then start using using those to
automatically build requests and then
fuzz on top of them because you know
maybe consider this situation you have
like a post request it has three ids in
it right if the first two are valid
objects then the third one is going to
be put into an SQL statement.
right? You know, and and so, you know,
if you just throw a random fuzzer at
that, right? Then it's it's uh and
you're just throw putting back tick and
everything in all of those of those
different fields, then you're not going
to catch the SQL injection in the third
uh ID. But nowadays, you know, where we
can easily say, okay, you know, we need
to grab we need to grab this ID, this
ID, this ID, and we have a way of really
easily identifying that um by looking at
the JSON body and correlating those, you
know. Um I think it should be much
easier for us to isolate each individual
um uh like endpoint or each individual
entry point for for data and then fuzz
at that specific level with valid values
for all the other other um um entry
points for data. Um, so I guess that's a
little bit the opposite of what you're
saying, you know, because in web, but
but I mean it applies definitely as well
that like like Fran was saying, you
know, there's lots of of value from just
throwing a basic fuzzer at it without
thinking about too much configuration.
Um, and then you know you'll get a lot
of results out of that. Yeah. And and
obviously like you know you're not just
spamming like this huge stream of random
bites which is fine. Um but you know
even just a very basic understanding of
like hey this expects like a JSON text
or hey this expects like a word document
um and with some understanding of what
that word document format should look
like then you can fast a bit smarter but
you don't have to like go all the way
and like try to build something too
complex you can just get get started
right away 100%. Yeah. And I I was also
um recently talking to someone who um
what information should I give about
this? Uh let's say someone who um is on
the receiving side of a lot of really
really complex extremely high impact
reports, right? Um to pivotal
technologies. Uh a and and one of the
things they were saying was and these
are things that probably you know the
researcher gets paid somewhere between
500,000 and a million dollars per per
buck. Right. As one does. Um yeah. Yeah.
Right. As one does, right? You know, you
know there there's maybe like Yeah. As
one literally one, you know, like no as
a very few, you know, a handful of
researchers in the world do. And one of
the things that they were saying was
oftentimes these this is like a prime
example of like taking the application
and bending it to your will, you know.
Yeah. Um and
and uh you know you have let's say you
got a delivery mechanism but you've got
like six different layers of okay I got
to break this technology I got to break
this technology I got to break this
technology along the way right and when
you when you if you're trying to make
more complex endpoint or um exploits
that really like get you all the way to
you know unauthenticated rce right a lot
of times you do have to address these
technologies that are a little bit um uh
lower down in the stack for example you
know when you're attacking IO iOS or
something like that. I believe a lot of
the bugs that that have come from that
are um attacking like the image parser,
right? Because you just like send an
image in a text message or something
like that and then iOS is like, oh, let
me parse this image and then they blow
everything up, right? Yeah. And um and
that's very relevant to this fuzzing
piece is like okay, you know, I have an
entry point and and my gadget then
becomes now the app is automatically
parsing a JPEG file, right? you know,
how do I use that gadget to to trigger a
insane flow of vulnerabilities? And the
answer to that has to be, you know,
you've got to be a dynamic hacker that
that can take, okay, now I've got this,
you know, app using this parser. I need
to fuzz the heck out of this JPEG file
and see where I can, you know, trigger
crashes and then kind of utilize that to
build out the full chain. Um, super
important fuzzing in those sort of
scenarios. Yeah, it's pretty insane
because some of these like like you said
these complex chains I think there was
this really I can't recall exactly which
format it was but it was this really
complex one like a year or two ago where
it was like this guy literally built
like a Turing machine right or Turing
complete machine using like all these
little gadgets. Oh my gosh, wasn't that
crazy? I saw that. Yeah, that was nuts.
Um and you know it all starts with like
this little overflow or like um uh you
know integer you know underflow or you
know use after three. Um, and you just
need to find that first gadget, right?
And then you can start building because
we can build that quite intuitively. Um,
and you know, just throwing a stream of
bites sometimes might just land that
one.
Yeah, man. It's crazy when you when you
think about gadgets, you know, we talk
about gadgets a lot on the podcast as
like a as a a building block of exploit
development. And uh and yeah, in those
complex situations, you know, like one
gadget might be now we're parsing a JPEG
file. And I'm like, "Oh my gosh." Like,
that is the shittiest gadget I've ever
heard of in my life, but is absolutely
essential to a lot of these exploits.
Okay. Um, chapter 8, chapter nine,
coverageguided fuzzing and fuzzing
everything. Um, tell me a little bit
about each one of those. Yeah. So, for
coverage guided fuzzing, I think, um,
this goes beyond like what I said
earlier, which is dumb fuzzing, right?
And this goes to like smart fuzzing,
which actually like what you described
earlier with LLMs is like a really
interesting way of of talking about
smart fuzzing, right? Because the goal
of smart fuzzing is that um with each
kind of new input that you fuzz um you
know, you randomize it or you send
something new, you get some information
back that tells you a little bit more
about what your input did to that
application and then you use that
information to then write smarter
inputs, right? um you might use that in
the binary sense to like reach more
parts of the application because you're
like hey now that my binary my my input
looks a little bit like a word document
um it opens up this function that calls
like pass word document right it doesn't
just reject it from the start and then
the fuzzer is like okay now I can just
keep building on this initial word
document and fuz on it instead of trying
to f something completely new um and
that's really the goal of like coverage
guided fuzzing is to build a better
understanding of the um target um and
from there um getting right deeper into
the application. Um and that requires
some setup, right? It's not like dumb
fuzzing where you can just get started
quick and and dirty. You need to write
harness. You need to like understand the
application a bit more. You need to
tweak your inputs. Um and that's what
this whole chapter about just getting
you into that um and understanding this
uh critical thing. Um, I think it's one
of those things that like everyone knows
is now kind of close to the standard of
fuzzing, like what you need to do to get
started in fuzzing, but it's always
setup is always challenging. It's always
difficult. And I kind of demonstrate
that through a practical example of how
we can just do that right away.
Absolutely. Yeah, that is that is
definitely a different a different
layer, right, when you're able to do it
intelligently. And uh my my mind
definitely thinks that you know as I as
it's spinning for web that we should
look at the ways that um the ways that
binary researchers have taken fuzzing
and utilized them because it is such a
more pivotal part of of binary research
and how to apply that to other areas as
well. You know, obviously mobile uses a
lot of of similar concepts as binary
exploitation, but also in web, you know,
how can we how can we isolate, you know,
certain paths of code and u and try to
fuzz those more thoroughly. Very
interesting. It's unfortunate because we
don't have as much introspection in
these blackbox contexts. And if we had,
you know, these web apps and we hooked
debuggers into it, then we could
essentially do the same thing. Yeah. Um
but not not always the case. Rarely the
case. Um and then and so I guess chapter
nine fuzzing everything is that sort of
similar to what you were saying there
with with coverage guided just kind of
extending that further. Yeah, I think
it's kind of like blowing up the
definition of what people typically
think about fuzzing because a lot of
people think fuzzing is just like this
pure binary thing, right? You just send
like like you said JPEGs or documents or
something. But what I'm trying to say is
that you don't just have to fuss that
you can fuss a web application, right?
you can f Java application that isn't
like a pure binary, but it's actually
still possible to fuzz it and use
coverage guided fuzzing for it with the
right tooling. Um, and you don't just
have to, you know, send binary blogs,
you can send text, you can send like um
um, you know, JSONs and so on and so
forth that allow you to f a lot more.
And I think this is something that the
web portion of research has been really
good at in that they they use that like
France just said. Um but um that's what
I'm trying to encourage as well for
people who just think of fuzzing as like
only for binaries is actually not the
case. You can use it for everything
else.
Very cool. Okay, chapter 10. We're we're
closing out here beyond day zero. What
is that last chapter entail? So this is
the be a good person uh chapter, right?
Because it's like you've got your your
zero day. What are you going to do with
that? Right? Um so I talk about
responsible disclosure. I talk about how
you can utilize that um you your person
you talked about at the Google event
right it was like obviously they take
the things they've learned and and apply
them to make it more secure um and and
so I kind of focus a bit on that because
I think it's really important um um
especially in this space um as we just
discussed with the CVES right it's
actually you know we think I think a lot
of people think of CDs as a collector's
item right to to add to the trophy case
and in some ways that's a good thing
right because that shows that you found
an actual vulnerability but A lot of
people also kind of take these things
for granted, right? Actually, the CV
system is like run by, you know, it's
community based system. It's run by my
job, but it's run by many people in the
community. Um, and it can break so
easily. Um, and so I try to kind of
expand that kind of thinking. It's like,
hey, it's cool to find a zero day. It's
cool to like make money from it. But
just think a bit more about how you want
to contribute back to the space and, you
know, um, be a good citizen in some
ways. Classic classic space raccoon
chapter lecture at the end. Yeah. Now
take now listen here y'all. Don't take
this and do anything nasty with it. I
don't know why you have a southern
accent in my in my head in this
scenario.
Yeah. Yeah. Um that that makes a lot of
sense, Eugene. And you know, I don't
know. There are a lot of people that are
a little bit more gray hat than they
should be in my opinion. Um and I've
I've always been inspired by your um
commitment to ethical ethical ethical
hacking like like really really ethical
hacking. Um uh it's definitely you're
definitely a good person to to have that
write that chapter at the end and and
inspire people to Yeah, exactly. Take
this with you. Don't go alone. Um
awesome, man. Well, I have to say, man,
I am um I'm pretty impressed that we
just went through all of those 10
chapters and you remembered what is in
each chapter and and were able to, you
know, succinctly represent it on the pod
because as somebody who I guess I don't
type it out, you know, and write it and
maybe I haven't reviewed it as many
times, but I very much have this problem
of
like especially when when Joel used to
be on the podcast, uh you know, I would
say something on the pod and Joel was
like, "Yeah, you said that on the pod
last week." And I'm like, "Shit." you
know, like I can't remember exactly what
I said. Um, so great job. You know,
clearly you spent a lot of time working
on this book and uh ironing out all the
details and I appreciate the succinct
representation of a lot of this um
giving us a lot of great takeaways. Um,
so let me let me see. The book is not
the only reason I had you on the podcast
today. There's also been a lot of a lot
of other really interesting um research
that you've put out uh over the past um
couple years since we last interviewed
you on the pod. So, I definitely want to
want to jump into that as well. But
perhaps I'll start off with this, man.
Like, where's the bug bounty? Have you
have you have you forsaken us, Space
Raccoon, our leader? like like where
have you are you going to are you going
to be participating more or do you think
you see yourself more solidly in the in
the vulner vulnerability research realm
and the the uh other realms that you
participate in security man yeah so this
is like a great question right because
like um part of me like was like that
Google web guy you talk to right it's
like coming from the offensive space I
would I think we all know like there are
some targets that are like rich veins of
gold that you know you They keep mining
again and again. And there's some
targets that like are like terminators,
right? You kind of like shoot them once
and you blow them up and then they come
back stronger, right? Um and that's
something I really admired um um when I
first started out bug bounty and and
this is something that I've been
spending a lot of time in, you know, uh
obviously my day job. Um how do you kind
of build things better um each time,
right? And use that offensive security
to to do that. So that has been a chunk
of my time. Um and I think for me I
think the boundary research has also
been super interesting because it gives
me more time to you know just do things
with less pressure. Um I would say uh I
can focus on topics that are interesting
to me but may not necessarily like lead
to a bounty right. Um and this and I
think this is something that allows me
to send things for conferences and
present at them and share some research
and be part of the community um but also
do it at my pace. Um and obviously a lot
of it has changed in in the past few
years as you were there, right? Um um
and that has given me some time to take
pause but um I think one thing that's
interesting about this community is that
people come in and out right they you
know get you know maybe they get a job
and they have to work in a job for a
while um and then after a while they're
like got this itch that I want to
scratch right and and they get back into
bug bounty and hacking. Um so yeah
definitely I see myself as like hey this
is kind of the season of life where I'm
in. Um but it may come, you know, a time
when I'm back into may come may come
back around. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Um so
yeah, definitely. I think it's just a
way to keep me sharp. But I love when
I'm doing found research right now and
diving brings a little brings a little
brings a little tear to the eye, Eugene.
You know, like it's the circle, man. It
is, man. It really is. And and and I
think you do see that often. you see
people cycle through and and some of the
most talented hackers I've ever met, you
know, yourself included, have have have
come in for a stint in Bug Bounty, you
know, made their appearance at the LHS
and at the top of the leaderboard and
then moved on to something that, you
know, more aligns with their their goals
of of lifestyle and and interest and
stuff like that. Um, yeah. So, as a
light, you know, as somebody who
considers them themselves a a bug bounty
lifer, it's it's sad for me because, you
know, I see my my friends come and go in
the in the, you know, um in the meat of
the community, right? you know, being in
the code. But, uh, you know, we always
get opportunities like this to sit down
and catch up and and and the the cool
part of it is that, you know, as long as
you are staying in offensive security
research, which most everybody does at
the end of the day because it's hard to
go it's hard to go back to blue team
after you've, you know, you've spent a
long time in red team like, "Wow, this
is so fun." um you know then we always
have things to compare notes on and and
you know cross-disciplinary lessons
learned that we can we can share um so
it it is fun man I I think that for me
as a as a full-time bug bounty hunter
that like I don't have a lot of
aspirations besides full-time bug bounty
because it affords a really nice
lifestyle of a lot of flexibility you
know good income um the ability to do a
fun podcast like this where you get to
interview brilliant people um But I I
definitely understand people that that
have different goals. Um Yeah.
Especially your goals, you know,
relating to governmental work, right? Um
so could you talk a little bit about uh
that? I don't want to put you too much
on the spot because I know Sure. For
sure. Yeah. But like like how how do you
get fulfillment from that? Why is that
something you chosen to do? So it's
actually pretty related to my bug bounty
journey as well actually because like um
the first bug bounty that I did was the
Singapore government bug bounty program,
right? uh where they're like hack hack
the government like make money. I was
like that's cool. That's really really
cool. Um don't mind if I do. Yeah. Don't
mind if I do. Right. Um and that's what
got me into this bug bounty space in the
first place. Um but actually one of the
first big bugs that I found was in um
Starbucks. Um if you recall back then it
was like Oh, I recall. Yeah. I mean
there was like a oh hey 3,000 bucks. And
you know somehow that made headlines is
like everyone was like why did they just
pay 3,000 bucks? But to me that was a
lot of money, right? Um but
uh not everyone might know this but like
a few years down the road there's
there's another headline um where
Starbucks um in Singapore was actually
hacked um and you know a lot of like um
people in the countries their details
were like leaked and sold online. Oh
wow. And that was like actually a point
of reflection to me because like
obviously like I was still a very active
participant in the Starbucks bug only
program but I was a good boy. stayed in
scope and all that, but I was like,
"Hey, you know, this guy may maybe they
found it in where I was looking at or
they found it somewhere else." Um, but
they made a different choice, right? And
they decided to like, you know, you
know, basically break people's privacy
and and you know, bring out catch out on
the situation. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And and
to me it was like, okay, um, so so how
can I like fix this, right? And that's
what really motivates me a lot in this
work. Um, and it's an interesting work
because like like making like like
Google, right? Um I I think they were
talking about the high assurance web
framework thing where they were able to
like eliminate XSS or like bring it down
to like one XSS a year, right? Um that
was something I observed in like Meta
like a while ago because um um when we
first did that event at Meta, right? We
we did find it. Um I think it was like
an SSRF or something and then I just
never found a similar one again, right?
And to me that was pretty interesting.
So it was also like intellectually like
challenging like it's like how do you
build this and you deal with a big
organization and you like try to
convince people to do things you know
it's not all technical. Um so to me that
was like an interesting thing but also
like there's this motivation behind it
as well which I very much attribute to
my start in bounty um which is why you
know it's such a wonderful space to to
always come back to. M so what you're
saying is you you're inspired by that to
say to look at these systemic
vulnerabilities that pop up in Buck
Bounty and in Buck Bounty we have such a
a clear motivator to um you know
highlight these systemic vulnerabilities
over time right financial gain um and
how do you how do you Google it? How do
you meta it and say, "All right, that's
never going to freaking happen again
like and and being on the side of of how
do I help eliminate entire bug classes
for a specific, you know,
entity as a whole." Yeah. And it's a
hard problem because like not everyone
has Google's budget or or meta's team,
you know, engineers like top engineers,
right? Um and that's that's the
interesting part and that's that's what
I think is interesting about public
service. This is exactly what I was
saying before, Eugene. My my green hat
is screaming screw you,
right? No, but but absolutely it's a
it's a ab 100% fulfilling problem, you
know, and to to solve, right? Because
you do reduce a lot of risk um and yeah,
I mean, as much as I hate to say it,
Google has done an excellent job with
that um on the XSS front. and I have
spent a lot of time banging my head up
against uh Google's XSS protections and
they're they're rough. So, I got pretty
close a month ago, but we can talk about
that offline. Me, too. I I I'll we will
talk about that off air. Yeah, I have to
compare some notes with you.
Um all right, let me let me let me take
a look at my notes here as we shift away
from um the the day zero to zero day
topic. So, we we've got the guilt by
association poning millions of
smartweight machines, which I do want to
talk about. Um, but actually, I want to
take a brief um jump into source code
review, and we touched on this a little
bit when when we were going through your
your um your book, but I wanted to kind
of just brainstorm with you a little bit
here on how LLM will assist source code
review in the future. Um because I I was
going through some of your blog posts
and I noticed I think I noticed in one
of those that you were using VS Code and
I've actually started recently using
Cursor and utilizing sort of Cursor's
LLM integration
while doing source code review. Yeah. Um
and it's been very helpful for kind of
closing some of the the gaps that I'm
like where did where does that function
go? And it's like ah it's over here. I'm
like okay solid solid. Um uh and so I
was wondering if you've played around
with that at all or if you see any any
pathway moving forward in the source
code review realm um with this new tool
that we've all got in our pocket. Yeah.
So, so I've definitely been playing
around with like a lot of these LLMs
that you know co-pilot um is one of
them. Um and and you know it's it's an
obvious problem for LLMs, right? Having
all that context about the code base and
I think that's the most powerful thing
about LLMs that kind of represents
almost like a shift from the one or two
years ago when everyone's like hey Sam
code right these like hardcoded rules
that are fairly brittle. Um either that
or you going to get a lot of false
positives, but with LLMs, you can build
a very strong context about the entire
codebase that you might not be able to
have in your head. Um and I think that's
the key thing that I see with LLMs and
one thing I hope that scales a lot more.
Um is that you don't just find the
surface level vulnerabilities, you
actually find the bombs that require
like deep understanding of what the
codebase is doing. Um which I actually
do think that LMS can be very good at.
Um so in the space I think it's I
haven't really seen that deep
understanding in a sense. Um it might
just you know you might just need to pay
for a lot more tokens. Um but that's
what I think is the end game there. Um
and once you hit that you know it does
feel like you can rely on LM for a lot
of these like research and findings.
Yeah, I don't know if it'll ever get to
this spot because cursor is such a new
new um you know technology or whatever
and or maybe it's a couple years down
the line, but it would be really cool to
see like cursor build into their models
you know like or build into their
product some security researcher
oriented features where it's like
um a aentified uh source and sync
analysis where it's like you know
actively navigating through the code
grabbing the pieces of snippets that it
needs correlating sources and syncs
Um, I think that there's room for a
product there, uh, for sure. And and as
I I don't know, I I I've also described
our tool in in um in Kaido shift shift
as like the cursor of of this. But I I
think the reason why I I say stuff like
that is because cursor was such a
mind-boggling moment for me when I
started using it of like, wow, uh, this
is a totally different thing than what
we're we're currently used to. And I
think there's a lot of applications for
that um in the security realm. Um and
and that is one of them. So definitely
definitely excited for that, man. No.
Yeah. I I think people should be so
excited for it. It's just like you just
got to try it, right? Like just just sit
down, use it, and then you might kind of
understand it and feel really like both
like oof and also like wow, right? Um,
and I think I think it's also like
interesting that you mentioned that
because it's true because a lot of these
like enterprise tools, um, they're kind
of meant for like, you know, companies,
organizations, and the blue hat
perspective is that, you know, I don't
want to get a high false positive rate.
You know, I want to make it simple. I
want my developers to get like a lot of
signals that are like accurate. But for
us boundary researchers, we're like, um,
sure, just give me all the false
positives as long as there's like some
gold in there because we have the
patience to go through everything,
right? Yeah. Um and so it is very and
otherwise we just be going through all
the code, you know, like
definitely definitely lots of room for a
good product there. My brain just starts
spinning every time I every time I think
about it. And I have seen some some
hackers recently that are um I guess
very respected um source code review
hackers saying I am very impressed by
recent you know LLM and their the job
that they've done in source code review
um when utilized properly. So that is uh
a sign to me that uh they definitely we
definitely need to be utilizing those
when we're when we're doing our source
code review process to to make ourselves
uh more efficient. And and I you know
I'm just coming off of a Google live
hacking event. So you know Gemini is
like I have a very lovehate relationship
with Gemini right now. Um but uh de
Gemini is is really interesting uh
because the sort the context window is
freaking massive. Yeah. Um, and that
just allows the LOM to make a lot more
um, human-like decisions because it it
really does have a lot of or even
superhuman decisions because it has so
much context. Um, a million tokens is
like a lot of tokens. Um, very cool
stuff there. I think they released like
a security focus one as well 2.5 for for
security. Um, yeah, I'd be interested to
see what products come out based on that
because there's a lot of opportunity
there. Me too. I need to I need to go
sus that. Um, okay. Uh, let's swing over
to guilt by association pwning millions
of smartweight machines. We covered this
actually on the pod a couple weeks ago.
I think we we messaged you about it, but
um, great write up, man. It's great to
see uh, this sort of thing and, you
know, very interdisiplinary, right? It
shows, you know, how web and firmware
devices and all of that sort of
integrates together. Um, IoT, you know,
of course, a scale is what we're talking
about here. I thought Reszo's comment
about your meme potential was pretty
solid of like how to find how much your
ex-girlfriend weighs. That should have
been the title, dude, for sure. Uh, I
can see you blushing right now as we're
saying it. Like, you would never ever
ever name it that. Um, so, um, that
that's pretty great. But, um, I
guess as I read this, you know, one of
the things that comes to my mind is
like,
uh, you have so many things you're
doing. You're writing the book, you're
doing the government stuff. Um, you bug
bounty is a thing that you've succeeded
at so much. Why do you take the time to
do something like like this and go after
a piece of you know
IoT a random a seemingly random piece of
IoT just for fun or or what what what
what's the route? Yeah. So this is a
well I think this is a funny story like
what actually sparked it was that like
one day like um I was actually on on a
holiday right and like went to the gym
in the hotel and then I there was a way
machine there and I looked at it I was
like why is there a Wi-Fi? Can we pause
for a second? Yeah. What? What? Weighing
machine. Yeah, that was what? This is a
scale. This is a scale. Do you guys not
say scale in Singapore? Oh, yeah. We say
weighing machine. Sorry. You guys say
weighing machine. That's so funny. I was
going to say No, no, no. You could say
you could call it whatever you want,
Eugene. Like we wing machine gets it
gets it across. I just, you know, I
totally didn't process it in my in my
head. You know, when I read it, I was
like, "Oh, smarting machines, of
course." you know,
but like um Reszo as we were talking
about this on the pod a couple weeks
back, he's like, "What? Why did why is
he calling it a weighing machine?" Like
it's just very interesting how um like
Singapore, you know, UK, Australia, US,
we've all we're all speaking the same
language here, but like there there just
be some out there random term, you know,
that's like completely different. Uh
yeah, it's very unlike other languages
dialects because uh like for example in
Japanese there there will sometimes be
you know different words that just
totally don't make any sense at all,
right? And you're like what the heck
does that word mean? And and uh and for
this scenario I totally understand
weighing machine, right? But somehow the
the language has evolved differently. Um
so I'm sorry to interrupt. You're you're
in the hotel. There is a smart weighing
machine there. Tell me about that. Um,
and it has this Wi-Fi symbol on it. I'm
like, why is there a Wi-Fi symbol,
right? And, you know, it kind of like,
you know, touched the screen a little
bit, figure out, yeah, triggered figured
out it was like connected to the
internet. I was like, all right, I'm
taking a picture of this. I'm going home
and I'm going to like start looking into
this. Um, but like part of it for me was
the motivation is that like I wanted to
kind of step out my my comfort space,
right? Because like um last year um I
presented at hardware.io, IO which is a
hardware research conference on like
monitors like monitor research um
display monitor research um and um but I
realized that at that time that I was
still very much stuck in like firmware
like client side software um I didn't
actually like you know reverse engineer
any of that uh um um hardware kind of
hacking and when I went there and I
think you know you we've also seen this
you know when we go to like hardware
hacking u life hacking events and people
are like doing crazy [__] right that we
would never do like and you connecting
wires, soldering, desoldering, you know,
reading a flash frame. I was like,
that's pretty cool that you can do that.
Pretty badass. Yeah. You know, people
are sometimes nice and they share the
firmware. Um, and that's when we can get
our hands on it, but to get there, you
got to like have those like hard skills,
right? And so I thought this was a good
opportunity to like step a little bit
out of my comfort zone to try that out.
Um, so what I did, the hardware hacking
portion of this like research was very
basic, you know, it's just connecting to
a UI uh port. Um, but it got me started,
right, because it forced me to like buy
the equipment and to like, you know, buy
the wires and try to connect it and try
to solder it or whatever. Um, and that
kind of was interesting to me. Um, what
was more fun, I guess, was that it
actually came out to something, right?
Because I just want to get a shell,
right? But then from there on, I was
like, "Okay, now what do I do?" Because
sure, I can like read my own weight or
change my weight, but that's not very
interesting. Um, look honey, I I lost 10
pounds.
Yeah, exactly. You're just like, cool.
What What's that matter, right? I'm not
I'm not putting on that postmarriage uh
20, you know? I'm doing great. It's all
in your head.
Yeah. So, yeah. And and and that just
became this whole thing where it's like,
damn, wait, you can actually like take
over everyone's way machines and change
their weight or whatever, I guess. But
like um like some of these companies,
they don't just sell weight machines,
they sell like blood pressure machines
or other like health devices. Um and
that was like pretty crazy to me. Um so
I actually learned a lot. So while it
was this thing that I came across, it
was actually something I've been meaning
to do for a very long time, which is
like try a bit more of hacking um and
kind of do this kind of inter
disciplinary research.
Absolutely. And it it is super fun. is
super fun to do. You know, like getting
approaching a target from a different
direction is really cool. Um, and you
you went up against a lot of a lot of
things in this blog post. As I'm looking
through it, you know, it's great that
you were able to, uh, grab the Java
source code a little bit there and have
something that was a little bit more
readable. But, um, you know, you see
that, you see the SQL injection in the
web, you see the firmware, you got the
UART hacking part, there's even some
Bluetooth in there. like it's definitely
an eclectic hacking experience which I
think is really cool about going after
some of these devices because if you are
looking for a way to like cut your teeth
in in various um realms of hacking then
you can just grab a device like this and
just be like I am going to understand
everything about this device you know um
which I think is something that I repeat
to newer hackers time and time again is
like when you
are like trying to approach a
target you your goal your primary goal
should be I am now the most
knowledgeable person in the world on
this thing like like the devs walk into
this room and I will you know to the
it's literally been to the point
sometimes where you I'll meet the devs
for the the software that I'm doing and
I'm like ah you're this guy I know what
lines of code you wrote because you you
know like I got access to these comments
and these comments have your name in
them and like that was [__] like what
you know like and and it's It's a blast.
It's a blast to to do that. Um I I did
want to ask, you know, there were some
Bluetooth components um to this a and
obviously that's a really um fun attack
vector because it's semi- remote, right?
Like you know when we're on the actual
physical device connecting UR cables and
stuff like that and getting a shell,
it's a high and it's really helpful to
have that debugging shell, but it's it's
you know, you have to be physically
attached to the device. So the impact is
a little bit meh. Bluetooth is sort of
like that that um that middle ground
where it's like okay I maybe I'm down
the street but I'm still popping your
scale. Um and then you know obviously
you went for the full remote route which
is obviously the most badass. So that
makes sense but but why did you shy away
from the Bluetooth realm? Yeah. So I
think for the Bluetooth realm um there
were kind of two parts to it. Firstly,
like there's already been a ton of
research into like the Bluetooth
protocols that um smart scales use. Um
and there's an open uh source project
called open scale um where people have
kind of reverse engineered understood
all of it. Um and while it was I mean
potentially possible to kind of you know
have an exploit over Bluetooth you know
buffer overflow whatever just by you
know because some of these were pure
binary um API calls from the mobile
device and then obviously on the uh on
the machine itself it would be um more
binary um it would also be very
challenging to kind of fully debug and
and build a proper exploit because I was
like this is bare metal ARM firmware
right I could emulate
But yeah, do I want to or do I like is
it worth it? It's literally a way, you
know, way machine, right?
And
right and it's possible, right? But do I
want to, right? Um and and so I thought
that's why I started to like shift more
towards like, hey, let me get to this
shell first, then I can understand this
a lot better. So it really depends on
like what information is available to
you at that time. Do you have the
firmware? Are you able to emulate it? Do
you have a shell on the machine? Um, and
so for me like YouTube was not a super
viable path. It was a possible path. If
I was like there's a pawn to own or
something, I would have tried
everything, right? But for me, I was
like, hey, you know, I just want to find
something fun. Um, and I'm not going to
like stress out too much about it. So
yeah, it's it's part of methodology as
well, right? You got to pick and
prioritize which attack vectors you're
going to use. Yeah. And and I think at
the end of the day, you went for the
attack vector that has the most impact,
right? which is the fully remote exploit
which um utilizes device to cloud
communication which is like I think
we've interviewed a couple um uh hackers
that go after IoT devices on a regular
basis on this pod and if there's like
one little tidbit of advice we could
give to to somebody who wants to go do
IoT hacking it is do not neglect the
device to cloud communication like that
is where the meat is time and time again
right um and so it's cool to see another
example of that here um that is seems to
be continuously revalidated and you get
maximum impact and you often get a
little bit softer attack surface because
um these the devs aren't really thinking
okay well who's going to get in between
the device and the in the cloud right
yeah a lot of times people they expect
that APIs are going to get hammered and
stuff like that but not that that that
extra layer there really cool to see man
um yeah I had in the notes as well just
kind of anecdotally um uh the at version
version thing. I like I had not seen
that as much before uh for SQL injection
for W bypass. I think that's a that's a
cool one. Um uh so I've definitely had
that one in my pocket. Um moving
forward. Yeah, that one's like a it was
interesting because it's a whole new
world because this particular W I was
coming up against was a BT web, right?
Which is a actually Chinese um W. Um so
no one like there's not a lot of
documentation in you know in in English
language uh about this web and bypasses
but you just need to enter the Chinese
name of this into search and then you
get like all these like posts in in in
Chinese about like bypassing this web um
and that's where you get a lot more
interesting gadgets. Um so that was like
an interesting thing that I learned is
like actually there's a lot more
information you know in all these like
foreign languages that would actually
have pretty big nuggets that you don't
get in English. Yeah. Yeah, I'm I'm a
little bit It's interesting because I I
have had that experience like several
times because there are some really like
niche um Japanese researchers on uh in
client side stuff in particular um which
is cool, but I'm sure it's just so much
more vast in Chinese. And for any of of
the people that are not, you nobody's
listening to this podcast, they don't
speak English, right? Because how are
you not worrying however much into this?
Um but you know English there is so much
vast vast amount of information and it's
so pivotal for people to be um you know
had that in their in their skill set to
be able to access all that and I'm sure
that it's the same case in Chinese like
because so much of the internet is is in
Chinese. Um, I'm sure I'm missing out on
a bunch of really cool techniques and
and every once in a while there
something is bridged, right, where it's
like, you know, you see this new tool
pop up. It t, you know, pops at the top
of all the benchmarks and it's from like
some Chinese researcher and you go to
the GitHub and it's like all in Chinese
and you're like, "All right, here we
go." You know, like now I got to figure
out how to use this [__] Um, very cool
to be multilingual in that in that
regard. Um, I did have one other
question uh about this write up that I
wanted to sort of run by you because
it's sort of in my mind this is like one
of those worst case scenarios like uh
super frustrating things that happened.
So, I'll read this quote. Despite
correctly figuring out the uh right bod
with my logic analyzer, my serial
connection kept returning gibberish.
After many hours of pain, I realized
that my cheap CP uh 21102 USB to TTL
converter was responsible for the issue,
and using a more reliable FT232 finally
got the results I needed. So, what you
were dealing with here was a a flaw in
the actual, you know, physical device
that you're using to interact with um
the the serial connection. Um, that
sounds horrible. Yeah. Uh, and like a
nightmare because for me, I just, you
know, I I'm struggling to get enough of
this stuff to work in the first place.
And then being able to realize like, no,
I am doing it right. Something's wrong
with that device. Yeah. You know, is was
really I'm sure that was a pain. Can you
can you talk about that? How did you
realize that that that was happening?
Yeah, because so so the interesting
thing with um like so so basically like
I was trying to get a bound rate which
is the kind of like um the rate of
symbols being sent um over time um and
it's important to get this right because
you're you're kind of converting from
like you know electrical signals to um
actual digital um information. Um so if
you get it wrong then you just your your
symbols are all going to be garbbled and
and so on. And I had initially gotten
the right um number um using like a
multimeter which is like you know
physical device you just use to measure
first um but then when I tried to enter
that number when I tried to use the
connection um using the USB to TTL
converter um it just didn't work and it
was driving me crazy right um and and so
you know uh as I mentioned in the blog
post I did kind of talked to this like
previous researcher had done it and he
was like no this this seems correct like
what you found um I was like um okay um
and Then I I I read online and about the
tools I was using if I was like
configuring it wrong and someone
actually had like a few posts on like
which was the best um converter to use
and then they said like hey this is
pretty pure prone to failure. Um and
they kind of be like okay well I've
tried everything must as well try this
thing. Um and and it was super annoying
because it actually did work. Um but
this was like really important lesson
for like hardware hacking where you know
I think we're very used in software and
web to for things to be like consistent
right. Um you can use an emulator even
um but it's supposed to work the same
way because it's cool. Um but in this
case there's hardware failure which is
um just just mind-blowing to me. So so
frustrating like like this is definitely
like I said like a worst case scenario
in my mind of like yeah I there's
actually something faulty with the cable
that is that is making that not happen.
Um, props to you for for getting past
it. And yeah, it's always great to get
that sanity check from a more
experienced attacker in that realm that
has a little bit of like a feel for it,
like, oh yeah, this something's off
here. Um, that that that definitely
helps. Joel Joel did that for me a
couple times when in my uh in my IoT
hacking experience, and I I so
appreciated that. Um, yeah. So, so I
guess without because we're we're
already quite a bit in in the pod, so I
won't I won't dive too far down this um
rabbit hole, but as far as serial
communication goes, you know, in this
scenario, you said you hooked up a
multimeter to it to it first. And as I
understand, you know, as data is coming
over these these wires, you know, you're
you're trying to figure out, you know,
the rate at which it's the the signal is
sort of oscillating there, right? And
that determines, you know, the baud rate
which is needs to be configured on your
serial reader to make sure that you're
getting you're interpreting the correct
um you know changes in in voltage as you
know a specific character or something
like that, right? So I if if you see
just a string of ridiculous looking
characters, then it it means okay
something's probably off and like the
delimiter is not correct or something
like that and you're not getting that
correct rate. Is that accurate? Yeah.
Yeah, that's pretty much what it was.
Yeah. Sounds super frustrating, man.
You're just looking at a a string of
like, you know, all sorts of random
characters. You're like, I know that
it's there. I know that the data is
something's there. It's speaking to me
that speaking to me. Yeah, that's great.
Okay. Um, I guess I'll ask one more
about this and then we'll we'll wrap it.
Uh but how did you how did you sort of
reverse engineer the um IoT
authentication flow for this specific
device? I mean that the the write up
outlines that process a little bit, but
for the for the reader that hasn't gone
through that um what would you say the
TLDDR on that is? Yeah, I think the
TLDDR is that like IoT like device
authentication is actually a fairly
fairly standard pattern. Um and you know
they have the bad pattern which is like
people just hardcode secrets on the
device you know it could be the serial
number it could be like a MAC address or
then the the good pattern right which is
like using certificates um and they use
the whole like public key infrastructure
kind of pattern to to authenticate um to
the server. Um so it's actually a fairly
common uh simple pattern and the end
goal is that like you got to read the
secret somehow. You got to get that
secret whether it's a certificate or the
like serial number that's stored
somewhere on the device. Um, and so once
I got the shell on this device, it would
just there were various like debugging
tools I could use and one of them was
like reading from memory, reading from
the database. Um, and that was what I
used to kind of extract it um, and
understand it. So that was the static
part of it because now I had the a
certificate I could try to like
authenticate to it directly myself and
figure out what went wrong. Um, and this
was actually like building like from a
long time ago at that same AWS hardware
event that you and I were at, right?
because if you recall, I I did have some
certificates um on a device back then,
but I didn't really understand it, but
now I do. Right. So, that's that's
progress, right? That's nice nice to
like look back and think about that.
Yeah, it's funny you referenced that
because that's I think you and I were
both kind of sort of cutting our teeth a
little bit at that event, right? And we
saw some of the more experienced hackers
and I think there was a search swap that
happened, you know, and then the traffic
was able to be proxied. Um and when I
saw that I was like, "Wow, that is
badass. I'm going to do that." And uh lo
and behold, you had the same idea and
here we are. There we go. Yeah. So that
was like a fun like um circle um moment.
Um and you know from there as well
because of the shell I could run
debugging like connections um and also
like a lot of debugging logs that also
give me like a bit more information
about what was going on. Um so that
helped me avoid like just pure bare
metal like arm reversing and really just
do a more dynamic approach to it. Yeah,
dude. As I'm sitting here listening to
you say that, I'm thinking this is
exactly why I made this podcast because,
you know, you and I had the privilege of
going to that life hacking event where
we learned so much about the these
things and and you're right, so many of
these patterns are repeatable across
multiple targets. And you know, you just
you go you have a couple experiences
with it, you know, through a friend or
at the live hacking event competitions
via the show and tell and then you you
you start seeing these patterns emerge
and you're you get confident doing it
yourself and that's how you grow as a
hacker, right? And that's really what I
credit for my for my you know rapid
growth as a hacker was showed up like I
was the plus one of a plus one to a live
hacking event in like 2017 and the
things I saw at that event and the
preceding
event changed my mentality on hacking
for a very long time because you get you
get exposed to you know especially if
you dig and you be like hey what did you
find? Hey what did you find? Hey what
did you find? you know, um, you get
exposed to different hackers techniques
and their different knowledge base and
you're able to sort of pull it all
together into one. Um, so thank thanks
for this Eugene. Thank you for for
taking the lessons you've learned in
that regard, considing them into um,
this blog post and then writing them
further into this book that you're
releasing because um, that is that is
how the community grows and you and I
are in a very privileged position to
have have seen a lot of this firsthand
and uh, definitely want to help
disseminate that to other hackers so
that they can grow as well. Yeah, for
sure. Thanks for having me back on. Of
course, man. It's been a great pod.
That's a
wrap. And that's a wrap on this episode
of Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh or if
you want to support the show, head over
to
ctbb.show/isord. You can hop in the
community. There's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes,
hackalongs, exclusive content, and a
full-time hunters guild if you're a
full-time hunter. It's a great time.
Trust me. All right, I'll see you there.
[Music]